RP Roger Pender

Senior Web Developer

- 562-413-9572
- <u>rdpender₃@gmail.com</u>
- Sacramento, CA
- <u>LinkedIn</u>

SKILLS

React, HTML, CSS, Javascript, JQuery, Node, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Wordpress, PHP, Next JS, Pardot, Addsearch, Salesforce.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development Certificate *University of California Davis*2018

Bachelor of Science, Animal Biology University of California Davis 2010 - 2014

ABOUT ME

Experienced full-stack developer with a passion for crafting tailored solutions from concept to implementation. Adept at both independent and collaborative problem solving, with a focus on driving client success. Committed to continuous improvement in technical expertise, coding skills, and staying current with the latest industry tools and trends.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Web Developer

Electric & Gas Industries Association (EGIA) / Jul 2019 - Present

Maintain EGIA and partner company websites. Create custom web pages using HTML, CSS, PHP, and Javascript. Collaborate with designers to turn mockups into functional pages. Enhance user experience of web pages by integrating feedback from users and internal member services representatives. Communicate with developers from other companies to add functionality and features to our sites. Manage EGIA's searchable database, update DNS records, and provide technical support to sales teams and users.

Teaching Assistant

UC Berkeley Full Stack Web Development Boot Camp / Sep 2019 – Mar 2020

Collaborated with instructors during class and conducted review sessions to solidify concepts with students. Taught the basics of programming including HTML5, CSS and Javascript, followed by frameworks and libraries such as React, NodeJs, and ExpressJs. Led breakout sessions focused on assisting students with their applications and debugging skills. Conveyed complex technical information in an understandable and effective manner. Graded weekly assignments and provided feedback on bugs or redundant code.

Student Mentor

UC Davis Full Stack Web Development Boot Camp / Oct 2018 – May 2019

Assisted students with coding issues by guiding them through paired programming. Worked both in-person and remotely.